Subtitles by explosiveskull
[ ♪ ♪ ♪ ]
[ GRUNTING ]
Fuck !
[ PANTING ]
Okay , I 've got ten numbers , four spots .
I need a four-digit code .
[ CLANKING ]
No , no , no .
Shit ! What now ?
Shit .
Jesus Christ .
Clues .
Shit . Okay .
That 's nothing .
" Follow the light to greener pastures . "
What does that mean ? What does that mean ?
Light ? What light ?
Light . Follow the light .
Green . Green book , yeah .
Greener pastures . Okay . Yeah , all right .
[ MUTTERING ]
[ GRUNTING ]
Oh !
" At any point in history , to watch another die ,
unveils time 's great mystery , while leaving you alive . "
Time . Time . Some kind of clock .
Shit .
Where 's the clock ?
I don 't see a goddamn clock !
" To watch another person die . " Yeah . Okay , yeah .
" To watch another person die . "
Oh , shit !
[ YELPING ]
[ STAMMERING ] Okay . They 're pointing ! Let 's see .
It 's time . It 's hands on a clock . Yeah .
That one 's four ! Four o 'clock !
Eight .
Six !
Two ! That 's the number , that 's the code !
Okay . Where 's the four ? Shit . Come on .
All right . Okay . Yeah , good .
Come on , come on ! Eight !
Six .
Oh , my God .
Where 's the ... ? Six , six , six !
Oh , God !
Two , two ! Yeah . Okay . Come on .
[ MUTTERING ] Come on .
Come on ! Why isn 't it working ?
Oh , shit .
[ YELPING ]
Come on .
Open ! Come on , open !
Oh , God , there 's no way out !
[ GRUNTING ]
Please get me out !
Shit ! No !
No !
[ SCREAMING ]
[ ♪ ♪ ♪ ]
[ SIRENS WAILING ]
PROFESSOR : Has anyone ever heard the saying ,
" A watched pot never boils " ?
Well , on a quantum scale , that may actually be true .
Does anyone know what the quantum Zeno effect is ?
Wow , guys , not all at once now .
[ CLEARS THROAT ]
Well , it may well be
one of the oddest things in quantum physics .
Simply put , observation stops movement .
Atoms won 't change while you watch them .
[ BELL RINGING ]
All right , that 's all the time we have .
Have a good holiday . See you after the break .
Happy Thanksgiving .
[ STUDENTS CHATTERING INDISTINCTLY ]
Zoey , can I talk to you for a minute ?
I read your paper on the quantum Zeno effect .
So , you want to be heard .
You want to share what you know ,
but only in the safety of your own dorm room ?
I 'll try and speak up more .
It might seem like reducing the number of variables
in your life will control the outcome ,
but life isn 't a science experiment .
You can 't contain your world forever .
Try doing one thing that scares you
over break , okay ?
Okay .
[ ENGINE REVVING ]
[ ♪ ♪ ♪ ]
JASON : Ray , it 's Jason . Listen .
You want to buy a boat by retirement , right ?
Well , keep focusing on these low-beta stocks ,
and it 's going to be a rowboat with rented oars .
By the end of the first quarter ,
the market 's going to see a 10-percent return ,
while you 'll be sailing away with 30 .
Uh-huh .
Hey , you won 't regret it .
I must be like the Mr. Miyagi of trading to you , Charlie .
" Mr ... ? "
Jesus Christ , kid , what year were you born ?
He 's this wise , old Japanese man
who taught a kid karate so he could beat up other kids .
Mr. Ackerman for you on line one .
100 bucks says I 'm getting a gift .
Congratulations , Mr. Ackerman . Are you celebrating ?
[ CHUCKLES ] Well , thank you . Thank you , Mr. Ackerman .
No . No , no , no , I couldn 't accept a gift .
Uh-huh .
A private jet . To Tahiti ?
Wow .
Your home there . Uh-huh .
Heh .
Now , that sounds like a hell of a weekend .
Man who catch fly with chopstick ...
accomplish anything .
You , beginner luck .
Wax on , wax off .
Hey , Gary . I , uh ...
I heard there was ...
an opening up front at checkout .
I could use the bump .
I 'm trying to move out of my mom 's .
It 's starting to cramp her style .
Look , I feel for you , kid .
I really do . You know , I do .
It 's just putting you out front would be bad for business .
Yeah .
Yeah , I 'm not cut out for
customer service shit anyhow , so ...
Ben ...
you 've got to find healthier ways to unwind .
Go outside , make a friend .
- I didn 't mean to ... - It 's fine , it 's fine . Sorry .
[ SNIFFS ]
Yeah . Thanks , Gary .
A messenger dropped this off for you .
It 's from Mr. Ackerman .
Of course it is .
This better be keys to a Tesla .
" For always thinking outside the box . "
Well , it seems like Mr. Ackerman has graduated
from sending single malts to boxes that don 't open .
Yeah . Rich people are weird .
Money can 't buy you happiness .
You better afford your own brand of misery , Charlie .
- Happy Thanksgiving . - Whatever . I 'll be in tomorrow .
[ RAP MUSIC PLAYING ]
[ PEOPLE WHOOPING ]
♪ They say sleep Is the cousin of death ♪
ALLISON : Hey , offer still stands .
Are you sure you don 't want to come
to my family 's for Thanksgiving ?
Thank you , but , you know ,
big family dinners aren 't really my thing .
Okay .
[ LAMP CLICKS ]
You know , I 'm really psyched about having time to myself .
I 've been wanting to take a stab
at one of those cuboid conjectures for , like , forever .
It 's really cool , actually .
They claim irreducibility
of three univariate polynomials
with integer coefficients and if that is true ,
then Euler 's concept of a perfect box can 't exist .
Wow .
[ CHUCKLES ]
You know , sometimes I wonder if you just make up words
because you know I won 't Google them .
[ CHUCKLES ]
[ DOOR OPENS ]
[ MUSIC PLAYING INDISTINCTLY ]
[ DOOR CLOSES ]
[ QUIET RATTLING ]
Not again .
[ ♪ ♪ ♪ ]
[ PANTING ]
[ PEOPLE SCREAMING ]
[ BEEPING ]
- [ ZIPS LOUDLY ] - [ GASPING ]
Are you okay ?
Yeah , I 'm sorry .
Well , I 'm out of here .
Okay .
[ SIGHS ]
Hey , this is for you .
It 's from your professor .
- Oh . - Wait .
You guys aren 't doing it , are you ?
[ SCOFFS ]
What ? No .
Well , have fun playing with your ...
box .
Bye , Allison .
Bye .
" Open new doors . "
[ ♪ ♪ ♪ ]
[ WHIRRING ]
" A chance to escape . "
[ CLICKS ]
MAN [ ON COMPUTER ] : Remember , the puzzle box is intuitive .
You don 't want to force it .
- [ CLICKS ] - [ GASPS ]
Snap , crackle , and ...
[ BOXES CLICK ]
Heh .
I hate you .
[ BOXES CLICK ]
Give this to the guy that failed eighth grade math .
Great idea , Gary .
This is the biggest waste of ...
" This serves as an entry voucher for Minos Escape Rooms . "
" Be the first to escape our most immersive rooms yet
and win $ 10,000 . "
- [ WIND WHISTLING ] - [ CAR CHIRPS ]
Hi .
This is the Minos building ?
- I think so . - Thanks .
Yeah , it 's going to kill me , I know .
Hi .
Yeah . I 'm here for the escape room .
ID please .
Thanks .
- Most guys buy me dinner first . - I need to collect your phone .
Really ? Why ?
You can 't be Twittering pictures of the puzzles .
- Okay . - Third floor .
Okay , thanks .
Thank you for your service .
[ ♪ ♪ ♪ ]
DANNY : Hold the door , please .
I always sneak in a second one .
- The waiting rooms can get so boring . - Mm .
[ ELEVATOR DINGS ]
[ PHONE GAME CHIMING ]
DANNY : Yes !
[ ♪ ♪ ♪ ]
[ CLEARS THROAT ]
WOMAN : Please have a seat . Someone will be with you shortly .
Okay , thanks .
MIKE : Quite the welcome wagon , isn 't she ?
JASON : Super friendly . Heh .
- Hey , Michael . Mike . - Amanda .
- Your name 's Amanda ? - Yeah .
- Isn 't that funny ? - AMANDA : What ?
I had a family dog growing up named Amanda .
She was a cute , little husky-collie .
Two different colored eyes , actually .
It was very unique . Yeah .
Cool .
Yeah , she was cool . Yeah , and then she died .
You know , dogs die .
[ CLEARS THROAT ]
Hitchhiking accident .
Can you still play video games ?
No . No , man . Unfortunately I can 't ,
so I just have sex with adult women to fill the time .
- Heh . Okay . - Yeah .
[ LAUGHS ]
Uh ...
Sorry . Hi .
- Hi . - AMANDA : Do I know you ?
No , I don 't think so .
Really ? You look really familiar to me .
You 're not on TV or something , are you ?
[ DOOR CLOSES ]
Well , this is going to suck . Hi .
Hey .
Sign-in sheet ?
Yeah , don 't bother . She 's preoccupied .
How are you doing ? Mike .
- BEN : Ben . - MIKE : Ben .
I 'm guessing you got a box too , huh ?
BEN : Yeah .
MIKE : Did it take you long to open it ?
BEN : It didn 't take me too long .
DANNY : Yeah , we all got boxes .
Opening it was the easy part .
MIKE : So , the website for this place made the games
look pretty fun , huh ?
Yeah . They 're basically like real-life video games .
- Really ? - JASON : So , you 've done
one of these before .
I 've done 93 rooms . Yeah , all the big ones .
Panic Room , Enigma , Basement ...
Breakout , Break In , Lock In . Lock Down , of course .
I 've done all the bunkers : World War One , World War Two ...
Cold War , Cold War Two : Pol Pot 's Revenge .
Uh ...
What about you guys ?
You must be really good at these , huh ?
Yeah . I 'm pretty good .
It 's not cool .
Yeah . You know , my nephew 's like you .
He 's completely obsessed . He burns through
all of his allowance money on escape rooms .
He 's the reason why I 'm here . He signed me up .
And apparently this room was rated
one of the top in the country on some chat room .
Yeah .
My weirdo rich client gave this to me as a gift .
It felt mandatory .
Yeah , paying people to lock me in a room
never seemed too appealing to me .
Yeah ? What changed your mind ?
- Ha , ha . Uh ... $ 10,000 . - MIKE : Yeah , me too .
That is a big chunk of change in my book , you know ?
Yeah . I 've been driving an 18-wheeler
since I had this injury a while back ,
and I 've been reading about these self-driving cars .
And I heard that the trucking industry 's
going to be the first one to get automated ,
so I 'm trying to just squirrel away a few nuts
before the robots come to get me .
- That was a real buzzkill , man . - It 's just my life .
DANNY : This one 's got to be really insane
for there to be a cash prize . The website said
no one 's been able to escape it yet .
If we 're able to do that , we 're going to have
so much street cred . You have no idea .
Are there rules and regulations ? What ?
DANNY : You just have to escape before the clock runs out .
Well , what happens if you don 't ?
Some guy comes in through the door
and explains all the clues you missed .
He makes you feel like a total idiot .
When does the game start ?
We are waiting for the Games Master
to come in to give us the story
and take us to the escape room .
Like , it 's a zombie apocalypse and we have to find
the cure before we get eaten alive .
I like that one . That one sounds good .
While the Games Master is looking for a parking spot ,
I 'm going to go smoke a cigarette .
[ ♪ ♪ ♪ ]
Oh .
Shit . Um ...
Hey , the doorknob came off .
- What , you broke it ? - Of course he did .
I didn 't break it , it broke .
Is that how you open a door in your house ?
- No . - Well , don 't be so rough with it .
Well , excuse me , miss . Ma 'am .
DANNY : Oh , my God , this is awesome .
You guys , you guys , I think this is the escape room .
What ?
MIKE : Wait , what ?
Okay , it looks like an oven dial , which means
it 's probably a combination lock .
All right , everyone search the room .
Wait , wait . It 's starting right now ?
- Yes . - Oh !
What are we looking for here , bud ?
DANNY : Anything that looks like a puzzle or a code .
Numbers are very important . It could be anything , anywhere .
Maybe under here .
Do you want me to hold on to this or is it ... ?
Yeah , just hold your knob there , guy .
Great . Very funny . Yeah .
[ ♪ ♪ ♪ ]
Hey , guys .
Hey , guys , these are all addressed
to the same guy , this Dr. Wootan Yu .
I mean , that 's got to be a clue , right ?
Maybe that 's the story .
Maybe he 's like an evil scientist
and we have to escape his lab
before he sews us all together
into some sort of medical abomination .
JASON : So , his evil lab has a waiting room ?
- Yeah . - No .
MIKE : Shit . Shit , shit .
Guys , look , look . I found a star-head screwdriver .
That 's got to be something , right ?
Great . So , we 're looking for screws ?
MIKE : Well , this isn 't a hammer .
- That 's a star-head , right ? - I think so . Yeah .
That 's Fahrenheit 451 .
MIKE : Oh .
All right , she 's got something .
[ CLICKING ]
[ WHIRRING ]
- What was that ? - I don 't know .
Did that do anything ?
MIKE : Whoa . Whoa , whoa .
Okay .
- All right , now that 's pretty cool . - Yeah .
Anybody got suntan lotion ?
What did you just do ?
I just thought the book was the code for the oven dial .
Turn it off , please .
Wow , it 's really throwing off some heat .
MIKE : Yeah , it 's warm .
It 's kicking some heat .
MIKE : What are those , giant oven coils ?
- AMANDA : Turn it off . - I 'm sorry . It 's stuck .
I can 't move it .
- Shit . - This is crazy hot .
- BEN : Can you shut it off ? - Shit . Okay .
Don 't touch anything else , okay ?
Hey , you , gamer boy , there .
What do we do ? How do we get out of here ?
When you 're stuck , you can ask for a hint .
A hint ? That 's an option ? Okay , great . Here we go .
Yeah , but it 's way more fun if we do it ourselves .
JASON : Good one , gamer boy .
I kind of want to do it ourselves .
Hi , excuse me .
- We 'd like our hint now , please . - Yeah , hello .
WOMAN : Please have a seat . Someone will be with you shortly .
No , yeah , excuse me , we 'd really like our hint , please .
- She said that last time . - So ?
She said it the exact same way . Same cadence , same tone .
Well , the actors they hire aren 't exactly Dame Judi Dench .
- Hello ? Hello ? - MIKE : I love Judi Dench .
[ ♪ ♪ ♪ ]
BEN : Yeah , I don 't think the snow globe 's going to help , man .
Hey . Uh ...
Hey , guys , there 's a lock over here .
Yes . Locks are a super important part of escape rooms .
All right .
Okay , it looks like we need a small key
to get to the other side of the partition .
That 's probably where the next clue is .
MIKE : Well , I 'm not going to be any help there
because I can never find my keys .
[ ALL CHUCKLE ]
Hilarious . Or we could just break it off .
There 's an extinguisher right here .
Yeah , good idea .
No , no . We shouldn 't have to use force .
That 's actually the one rule I forgot to tell you . My bad .
- Good one . - Great .
You 're really good at breaking stuff , huh ?
It 's plastic .
[ WHIRRING ]
What was that ?
MIKE : That 's that same sound , right ?
JASON : Man , what the hell did you just do ?
Oh ! Oh .
Oh , shit .
Oh , shit , that looks real .
They 're just trying to give us a scare
as part of the immersive experience .
AMANDA : What the hell , are they paying you ?
DANNY : No , I just know how to have fun , I guess .
Heat stroke is your idea of fun ?
JASON : It 's getting warm .
Hey , it 's not that bad . Just take off your jacket .
JASON : Hey , does anyone else have a problem with this ?
Hey , guys , I think I 've got the key .
Whoa , hey , there . Listen , short stuff ...
let 's talk about this before you bring tiki torches
- out of the walls , okay ? - Hold on now . She 's got a key .
Why don 't we stick it in the keyhole ?
Okay , yeah . My bad . Let 's try it .
Give it a shot , come on .
WOMAN : Please have a seat . Someone will be with you shortly .
Well , that 's creepy as hell .
[ PHONE RINGING ]
Fine . Yeah . I 'll get it . Move .
Hello .
VOICE [ ON PHONE ] : Welcome to Minos ,
the world 's preeminent designer of escape rooms .
To get the most out of your game ,
we recommend following all posted rules .
Hey . Hey . Hello ? Hello ?
Who was it ? What did they say ?
It was a recording .
It said to follow all the posted rules .
What posted rules ?
Oh , shit .
- DANNY : No . - JASON : Did I do that ?
No , no . What the literal hell ?
Please stop . Okay , I 'm done .
No , no . You 're stressing everyone out here , okay ?
Just go get some water and take off your damn jacket .
JASON : We 've got to find a way out of this Easy-Bake Oven .
ZOEY : Okay , look at me , look at me . Amanda .
JASON : Oh , shit .
Are those fans ? Are they blowing hot air ?
We 'll just get some water , okay ?
Come and get some water with me .
I 'm fine . Okay .
DANNY : Yeah , it 's getting hot ,
but nothing is going to happen to us .
- BEN : Ovens have fans . - DANNY : True , but so what ?
We 've got to find the posted rules .
I don 't care about the posted rules .
It might be colder by the windows .
JASON : I 'm burning up .
Come on , how do we get out of here ?
DANNY : You 're not going to solve anything by sitting on your ass .
MIKE : I 'm not sitting on my ass . I 'm on my hands and knees .
JASON : Hey , what are you three doing ? Look for something , come on .
BEN : It 's too hot . What do you want me to do ?
JASON : Ladies , come on , enough with the water .
Get over here and help us look .
DANNY : We just have to figure out what the clue meant .
MIKE : Hold on . What 's this ?
BEN : There 's no way this is part of the game .
Where are all the clues at , huh ?
Ah !
Guys , come on . It 's getting hot in here .
We 've got to find something to break this door open .
DANNY : Dude , we 're not supposed to use force .
Come on !
When is this over ? How do we get out ?
BEN : It 's getting hotter . We 're being baked alive .
DANNY : Guys , relax .
JASON : This is sick . Who does this ?
MIKE : Come on , Ben .
BEN : What do you want me to do ? I can 't see anything .
DANNY : Guys , we need to focus and find the clues .
MIKE : It 's like 150 degrees in here .
[ WHIRRING ]
Hey . Hey , Zoey , the painting .
BEN : Oh , my God . There 's an exit .
MIKE : Oh , hot dog , look at that .
Zoey , do that again . Whatever you did , just do it again .
Hey , guys , it 's a duct . It could be a way out .
DANNY : Guys , there are more coasters here .
BEN : Get on the coasters .
Everyone try pressing down at the same time .
BEN : God , even the table 's hot .
[ ALL LAUGH ]
- Is that it ? Did we win the game ? - Yeah .
- JASON : I 'll go first . - All right , we win the game .
Whoa , whoa . Wait , you 're not going to just leave us
with our dicks in our hands .
Does anybody prefer this guy go instead of me ?
- That 's what I thought . - BEN : Really ?
Where does it go ?
- How deep does it go ? - JASON : It goes pretty far .
Jesus Christ .
BEN : It 's broiling .
MIKE : It 's not getting any cooler in here .
Oh , my God . I 'm so excited for the next room .
- The next room ? - AMANDA : Jason ?
Hey , I think I found a way out ! It 's blocked by a grate .
- Mike , bring that screwdriver . - Yeah ! It 's in my pocket .
Someone get it out of my pocket for me . Come here , Amanda .
Does anybody want to take the screwdriver ?
- I 've got it , I 've got it . Go . - Are you sure ?
Yeah . Go , go .
- Just do it . - You 've got this , Mike .
BEN : Go , man . It 's not getting any colder . Hurry up , go .
- JASON : Mike , where you at ? - I 'm coming .
Hey , hey . Just think of it like interactive dinner theater .
Jesus Christ , you 're not helping me here , man .
Okay , yeah . I 'm making it worse . My bad .
JASON : Are you going to come today or what ?
- Watch your face down there . - You watch your face up there .
Come on . Come on , come on .
Hey , I got it . You guys , come on !
Do you want to go ? Amanda , you should go .
Okay . Okay , here , take these .
Okay . He can take that . I 'll hold it .
- Okay . - All right , come on .
You 've got this .
BEN : All right .
I feel like we 're avoiding the inevitable conclusion here .
We 're running out of hands .
I 've got an idea . Come here . Put your foot on here , please .
- Ow . Ow . Ow . - Okay .
This is the worst game of Twister ever .
[ SIZZLING ]
[ WHIMPERING ]
BEN : Can we move a little faster , please ?
- It didn 't work . - Shit .
Okay , maybe it needs to be full .
- I think I 'm going to pass out . - Okay .
Come on , come on , come on . Come on !
You can move your foot . Okay .
- It worked ! - Yes , yes .
[ CRYING ]
[ EXPLOSIONS , GUNFIRE ]
[ PEOPLE CRYING OUT ]
[ COUGHS ]
Amanda ?
Hey , why don 't you just go help her ?
We 'll fill the glasses .
Stop being chivalrous , dude .
No one here wants to have sex with you .
- Go ! - Okay .
DANNY : Nice . Really nice , Ben .
Shit .
- Come on . - Okay .
She 's clear . Go , go , go . Come on .
Come on , you son of a bitch , please .
Come on , come on , come on .
Amanda ? Amanda , I 'm here .
Okay . Good .
What 's wrong ? You can breathe . You 're not stuck .
Breathe in with me . One , two ...
[ GASPING ]
Two more .
This is not real . You 're not stuck .
You 're okay . I 'm here , okay ? I 'm holding your hand .
I promise I 'm right here . You 're okay .
BEN : Okay , we need one more . We just need one more .
Shit , we 're out of water .
What are we supposed to do now ?
How would I know ? You 're the expert here .
We 're really close . We 're really close , I promise .
This is all your fault , you know .
- What ? - DANNY : You 're the reason
that Amanda drank all of our clues .
ZOEY : Jason 's right there , okay ?
How was I supposed to know that the water cooler was ...
Oh , no .
- Well , that 's not good . - DANNY : What the fuck ?
My flask . My flask .
You 've had that the whole time ?
Oh , my God .
Come on ! Yes . Yes .
Do you want to burn to death ? Let 's go !
[ ALL EXCLAIMING ]
JASON : What the hell ?
Oh , Jesus . Talk about immersive .
Immersive ? What the hell is wrong with you ? That was real !
- They 're just messing with us . - Are you kidding me , dude ?
Look , it went off right as I cleared it .
Okay , I must have triggered it .
The Games Master wants us to think we barely made it .
I can 't be the only one .
Hey . It 's ten grand and I don 't lose .
Well , I 'm out , okay ?
Hi . Okay , I 'm done .
I want out . You let me out of here now !
MIKE : You think they 're watching us right now ?
- Come on . - " Sai-San lock and co . "
All right , so we need another key .
Give me your phone . I 'm calling the cops .
DANNY : Think about it for a second , okay ?
What has actually happened to us so far ?
Nothing . What will you tell the cops ?
AMANDA : I don 't know , maybe that they locked us
in a giant oven and tried to cook us .
Is open flame a common occurrence in these things ?
- Not really . - Not really .
Give me your goddamn phone .
MIKE : You do have a phone . How did you get a phone in here ?
I snuck it in .
- There 's no signal . - MIKE : Typical .
Well , yeah . We 're in a giant concrete building .
Guys , we can figure this out . I mean , look at this place .
I mean , the only thing missing is the hot chocolate .
MIKE : All right , how long do you think this game is going to last ?
I mean , I don 't know . I did one that had , like , five rooms once .
Five ?
Five rooms ? Okay .
Okay . So , that means we just need to do that four more times .
I 'm kidding . Come on , guys , we can do this .
That was the hardest room by far , right ?
They front-loaded it , right , Danny ?
Yeah . I mean , I 'm sure they can 't afford
to light every room on fire .
MIKE : Exactly . Look at it .
This place is a goddamn tinder box .
Hey . Hey , second lock , guys .
It looks like we need a seven-letter word .
Let 's spread out and see what we can find .
Okay .
MIKE : " You 'll go down in history . "
What about this ? Could that mean something ?
" You 'll go down in history . "
You 'll go down in history . You 'll go down in history .
Maybe a president 's name ? Maybe a president 's last name .
What presidents have a seven-letter last name ?
Madison , Jackson . Lincoln , Johnson , Harding .
- Whoa . Slow down there , Rain Man . - That 's offensive .
What was the first one ? Madison .
M-A-D-I -
- S-O-N .
No , that didn 't work . What was another one ?
- Johnson . - Johnson . Okay , Johnson .
J-O-H-N-S-O-N .
No , what else ?
Yeah , Jackson . J-A-C-K-S-O-N . What 's the next name ?
- MIKE : Try Lincoln . Lincoln . - JASON : Lincoln ?
L-I-N-C-O-L-N .
There are letters here , but there are nine .
JASON : No , that doesn 't work either .
♪ How the reindeer Loved him ♪
♪ As they shouted out With glee ♪
♪ Rudolph The red-nosed reindeer ♪
♪ You 'll go down in history ♪
[ HORN HONKS , TIRES SQUEAL ]
Dasher , Dancer , Prancer , Vixen ...
Comet , Cupid , Donner , Blitzen .
- You 'll go down in history . - JASON : What is he talking about ?
- It 's " Rudolph . " - JASON : Did he say " Rudolph " ?
- Yeah , try " Rudolph . " - All right , " Rudolph " it is .
Bingo !
Look at that . Hey , he helps .
MIKE : All right .
DANNY : Hey , see ? It 's going to be fine from now on .
No more scary shit .
Hey ...
are you okay ?
Yeah , fine .
MIKE : Look at this , going from hot to cold .
You know , that 's how you get sick .
[ WHIRRING ]
[ GASPS ]
Whoa .
[ CHUCKLES ]
Dumb question . Are we outside ...
or am I stone-cold tripping ?
[ SIGHS ] I don 't know , man . This place is really cold .
It 's 30 degrees and dropping .
Real fun game , huh ?
- MIKE : Echo ! - JASON : Hey .
BEN : This whole place is bullshit .
The sooner we figure this out ,
the sooner we get the hell of out here .
This is beautiful . Oh , man ,
I could hang out in here for a while .
It 's like ice skating .
- Into the great wide open , Danny ! - Be careful .
[ LAUGHS ]
Keep going , man . Check it out .
- BEN : Yeah , where are you going ? - MIKE : Let him figure it out .
[ GRUNTS ]
[ ALL LAUGH ]
- [ CRACKING , RUMBLING ] - JASON : Whoa !
- AMANDA : Guys ? - Hey , nobody move .
Come on , guys . Relax , okay ? It 's fine . Look .
Hey , don 't do that .
It 's just a sound effect .
The ice isn 't cracking .
They are watching to make sure
nothing bad happens to us .
I mean , can you imagine the lawsuits
if one of us actually got hurt ?
Learn to have some fun in your life . Jeez .
Whoever did this is an artist .
What is that ?
- Danny , come on back . - Get over here . Hurry up , Danny .
DANNY : Shit .
JASON : There 's freezing air
coming through those vents .
ZOEY : Come on , Danny !
AMANDA : Danny , get back here .
Okay . I 'm coming . I 'm coming .
- Shit , that is cold . - BEN : Get together for body heat .
- Oh , the air is freezing . - AMANDA : Stay close .
- This is awesome . - BEN : Why are they doing this ?
- AMANDA : Come on , get closer . - BEN : Oh , my God , that 's cold .
We should look for clues .
Hello ?
Hey .
Open , open , open .
[ ♪ ♪ ♪ ]
Hey .
- Yeah , do you want to look ? - Yeah .
" True north is a lie . "
MIKE : What are you looking at ?
Good boy .
Hey , I found a door . We need a small key .
Where did that come from ?
One coat for six people ?
You know what they 're trying to do , right ?
They want us to fight over limited resources . Jesus Christ .
Hey . Hey , assholes .
It 's not going to work this time , okay ?
We 're going to share it .
Zoey , you go first .
Thank you .
[ SPLASHES ]
[ GRUNTING ]
- BEN : Shit , that 's cold . - Ben .
[ MIKE YELPING ]
Shit ! Oh , that 's cold .
JASON : Hey , false alarm , everybody .
A giant fishing hole . How did you miss that ?
What are we supposed to do with this ?
There could be a clue at the bottom .
Oh , really ? Why don 't you go dive in and check ?
Okay , it just feels like I 'm playing
the world 's funnest game with the world 's meanest people .
I can 't feel my goddamn leg .
- Hey , guys . - Mike ?
Ha !
Look , I 've got it .
I mean , I 've got something .
I just climbed a tree for , like ,
the first time in my goddamn life .
Danny , tell me this is something we can use .
Yeah , totally . It 's a clue .
Finally , something I 'm good at .
You mean you can stand over a hole and hold a stick ?
Wow , thank God you 're here .
I understand you 're cold right now ,
but if you say something disrespectful to me
like that again ... I 'm going to give you
the slap your parents should have years ago .
- BEN : Oh , really ? - That 's amazing .
With pleasure .
So , what are we supposed to do now ,
just stand here and wait to catch a clue ?
DANNY : Well , it 's probably really deep .
MIKE : Yeah , I 'm about 20 feet down already .
DANNY : I can 't even see .
JASON : This is a waste of time .
MIKE : You think this is a waste of time ?
- JASON : Yeah . - It 's so goddamn cold .
JASON : I do . I think it 's a distraction .
BEN : I think this whole thing is a waste of time .
MIKE : I climbed up to the top of that tree .
I found a fishing rod up there .
True north .
What ?
What are you trying to tell me ?
True north is a lie .
They 're probably watching us , laughing their asses off ,
as we stand around a hole like a bunch of morons .
- We probably just have to wait . - Oh , screw that , man .
Give me this , Mike . Mike , give me the pole !
Why don 't you chill out , man ?
You don 't know what you 're doing , man .
You don 't even have the release open .
MIKE : Don 't let it out .
You 've got to drop it to the bottom .
Shit , that 's deep .
Screw this . Here , take this .
MIKE : Give me that back .
JASON : I 'm sorry , all right ?
I hate the cold and it makes me go crazy .
I have to spend every winter in Kauai .
Me , too . When I 'm not in the South of France .
[ SCOFFS ]
Hey , where 's Zoey with that jacket ?
I need that jacket .
[ GASPS ]
Yes .
Hey , you mind not smoking that around me ?
Pull up the line . I found something .
- Pull up the line . - MIKE : What ?
Everyone , I found something .
MIKE : What do you got there ?
DANNY : Another clue ? Impressive , Zoey .
- What is it ? - Okay .
- A magnet , of course . - I 'm with you . Okay , okay .
Okay , try it . Try it now .
All right , all right . Stand back .
There she goes .
Zoey , your turn is up .
Right . Sorry .
Oh , shit . Okay . I 'm on the bottom .
No , I 'm hooked .
All right , I 've got something .
I 've got something here .
Yeah , I 'm definitely hooked .
Oh , God .
- Nice . - God , that 's heavy .
ZOEY : Okay . Okay , I 've got it . I 've got it .
MIKE : You 've got it ?
We 've got a key or something .
MIKE : You 've got it . Okay .
DANNY : That 's got to be the key to the door .
- Who thinks of this shit ? - BOTH : One , two , three .
Okay . One , two , three .
- Okay . - Shit , that is solid .
- Hey , Ben . We need your lighter . - Oh , yeah , that 's a good idea .
What do I get in return ?
I won 't take any of your One Direction CDs .
[ CHUCKLES ]
Come on , just give it , man .
All right , you want the lighter ?
Here .
There you go .
[ SCOFFS ]
- Okay , I 'll get it . - MIKE : Thanks , Danny .
I don 't know .
Man , that is buried right in the center , isn 't it ?
Oh , and you 're welcome , by the way .
DANNY : Thanks a lot .
[ SCREAMS ]
Danny ?
What was that ? What happened ? Where 's Danny ?
Say something . Where is he ?
He just fell through .
JASON : What do you mean , he fell through ?
He 's under the ice !
Danny ! Danny ! Danny !
All right , I 'm going in after him .
No , no . There is a current under there .
Even if you find him ,
you will not make it back to the hole .
AMANDA : Danny , where are you ?
MIKE : He 's being dragged around under there .
AMANDA : Danny !
Danny , where are you ?
- MIKE : Danny ! Where did he go ? - Do you see him ?
- I can 't see him . - Danny !
Shush , shush , shush ! Shush !
- AMANDA : Oh , my God . Danny . - JASON : Where is he ?
[ DANNY GRUNTS ]
ZOEY : Danny . Danny , Danny .
[ ♪ ♪ ♪ ]
What happened ?
You were right .
This is real .
How did it happen ?
Hey !
- How did it happen ? - What ?
How did Danny fall in ? You 're the only one who saw .
He was there and then it exploded and then he fell .
You threw him the lighter and somehow you 're perfectly fine ?
I threw it across the ice . I was just being an asshole .
Yeah , you threw it to the exact spot
that just happened to collapse ?
Are you saying that I did it ?
Yeah , hey , your words , not mine .
Danny kept talking about a Games Master .
Yeah . Well , maybe he 's already here .
Games Master ? I work at a grocery store , all right ?
I mean , Jason 's the one here
with the whole American Psycho vibe .
Mike , you 're like the creep at the truck stop .
And Zoey , I 'm really sorry ,
but it seems like your parents locked you in a basement
until you finished all your homework .
And her . What about her ?
I mean , where did she get all the scars ?
I served in Iraq , asshole .
Oh , so you 've had military experience ?
So , that makes you like a ...
psycho Xena .
I 'm just saying here , I 'm , like , the least suspicious one .
JASON : Okay , you know what ? Shut up !
None of it matters , all right ?
Whoever did this to us will let us freeze to death ,
if we don 't get the key out of that ice .
Okay . Since Ben 's lighter is gone ,
we have to surround it with as much body heat as possible .
Ben 's lighter is gone ?
Danny is dead .
JASON : Do you know what happens when you get hypothermia ?
Huh ?
You get disoriented and confused .
And I don 't care how smart you are
or how many books you read ,
you won 't remember how you got here ,
much less how to get out .
You guys get over here
and put your hands on this ice .
[ ALL SHIVERING ]
JASON : I know it 's cold , but it 's melting , guys .
Come on , just keep your hands on it .
Hey , jacket .
MIKE : Let me take it for a minute . Oh , that 's cold .
Okay . Here . Jesus .
[ SHIVERING ]
How are you doing there , Mike ?
- Oh , you know . - Need a break ?
Mm-mm . No , I got it .
I 'm okay . I 'm okay . Thank you .
I just can 't figure it out .
Who would do this ?
Someone who thought of every detail .
[ ♪ ♪ ♪ ]
[ COUGHS ]
- Mike ? - ZOEY : Hey , Mike .
Hey , put your back against the tree .
- MIKE : No , I 'm okay . - ZOEY : We 're here , okay ?
[ ALL CHATTERING ]
Hey , we 're here , we 're here .
- Jason ? - Where 's he going ?
AMANDA : He 's got the key . You guys , come on .
- Get up , come on . - ZOEY : Okay .
- Where is it at ? - BEN : Hey , Jason .
Where 's it at ? Where 's the door ?
- Jason ! - Get off me !
Where 's the door ?
BEN : There 's a door ?
Open it .
Open the goddamn door ! Open up !
Open this door ! Open the goddamn door !
[ CHIMES ]
Hey , you did it , you opened a door .
- Move . - ZOEY : Jason ! Let 's go !
Wait .
- [ RUMBLING ] - [ PANTING ]
Oh , shit !
- BEN : Wait , wait . - AMANDA : Zoey , come on !
BEN : Wait for me !
ZOEY : Ben !
[ WAILING ]
[ ALL PANTING ]
Hey , is everyone okay ?
BEN : I can 't feel my extremities .
What is that ?
[ LIGHTS CLICKING ON ]
MIKE : Uh-huh .
Sure , why not ?
Well ...
glass half full , at least it 's warm in here .
- [ ALARM WAILING ] - [ RUMBLING ]
Oh , my God .
MIKE : What 's happening ? What is that ?
- Are we moving ? - Yeah . Hold on .
[ WHIMPERING ]
- What , are we going up ? - BEN : Yeah .
JASON : How many floors is this building ?
AMANDA : 15 to 20 floors .
Well , I 'm guessing they didn 't shoot us up here for the view .
[ PHONE RINGING ]
Okay .
How are we supposed to answer that ?
Hello ?
[ DIAL-UP TONE SCREECHING ]
- Son of a bitch ! - [ EASY-LISTENING MUSIC PLAYING ]
God , that 's loud . And it sucks .
Oh , great , we 're going to die to elevator music .
Guys , hey , this door up here doesn 't have a handle .
I think we 're looking for a doorknob .
Let 's see what we can find .
♪ Listen to the music Of the traffic in the city ♪
♪ Linger on the sidewalk The neon signs are pretty ♪
♪ How can you lose The lights are much ... ♪
Hey , the eight ball , it 's missing from the pool table .
Look at that . I 'm going to check these cue racks .
Maybe there 's something over here we can use .
[ DIAL-UP TONE SCREECHING ]
- Hey . Mike , stop ! - ZOEY : Mike ! Mike !
[ SCREAMING ]
JASON : Get away from the edge . Grab onto something .
- Oh , Jesus Christ . - ZOEY : Mike , step back ! Mike !
- AMANDA : Guys , come on . - Hey , get off the floor !
Mike , hurry up ! Mike , get off the floor .
- Shit . - BEN : Did you see that ?
JASON : What the hell 's going on ?
[ DIAL-UP TONE SCREECHES ]
[ SONG RESUMES PLAYING ]
What is this , like , musical chairs ?
MIKE : What do we do now ?
BEN : I don 't know , try not to die .
Hey , Amanda , just think about this .
Just let me try this .
MIKE : Go , go , go .
[ GRUNTING ]
- Oh , shit . - Are you okay ?
Yeah , it 's just wet . Oh , shit .
Okay , here I go .
Hey , what about the radio ? Maybe it 'll shut the music off .
No , I don 't think it 's connected .
What about those coolers at the top ?
Okay .
JASON : Maybe the handle 's in there .
MIKE : And keep your eyes peeled for that eight ball .
Okay .
MIKE : Yeah , the craftsmanship in here is just terrifying .
I hate this room so much .
Guys , I 've got a lock box .
All right .
It looks like I need four numbers .
All right , try one-two-three-four . Just to see .
I guess we know Mike 's PIN code .
[ BEEPING ]
Nope .
MIKE : All right . Try one-one-one-one .
You know , go back to the basics .
BEN : What ? One-one-one-one ?
AMANDA : Uh , nope . That 's not it .
It 's a giant sliding puzzle .
- Zo ? - MIKE : Zoey ?
- Zoey , what are you doing ? - Zo ?
Careful . Careful , careful , careful .
[ PANTING ]
AMANDA : Good job , Zo .
MIKE : That 's good , Zoey . Just stay there .
BEN : Where are you going ?
I can 't hang around on this bookshelf all day .
This was a bad idea . Oh , God .
Come on . One , two , three .
[ BOTH GRUNTING ]
Up you get .
Thanks .
Okay .
[ TILES CLACKING ]
[ PANTING ]
[ DIAL-UP TONE SCREECHING ]
Oh , shit !
Oh , my God ! Oh , my God ! Oh , shit .
Jason , hold on !
[ SCREAMING ]
I 'm okay . I 'm okay . Oh , God . I 'm okay . Oh , God .
Are you all right ?
Keep going . Keep going . I 'm okay .
He 's okay . It 's okay , he 's okay .
You 've got this . You 've got this .
[ DIAL-UP TONE SCREECHES ]
[ SONG RESUMES PLAYING ]
Is there anything we can do about this shitty music ?
[ GRUNTING ]
Oh , God !
Oh , my God .
BEN : Jesus Christ .
Hey , I 've got it .
What ?
Got it .
There are colors . I see yellow ...
black , and blue .
Yeah , yeah , yeah , and we 've got two lines and a circle .
It 's like Morse code . Maybe it 's Morse code .
Stripes and circles . They 're billiard balls .
The yellow stripe , that 's a nine .
Nine . Next .
The black ball , like , that 's the eight ball , obviously .
- Eight . Two more . - ZOEY : Blue stripe , that 's ten .
Try one-zero .
- One-zero . Goddamn it . - [ DIAL-UP TONE SCREECHES ]
- Shit . - Shit !
- ZOEY : Go , go , go . - JASON : Get off the floor .
ZOEY : You 've got it , Mike . Come on .
Oh , my God .
[ BUZZING ]
JASON : Hold on , okay ?
[ ALL SCREAMING ]
That thing 's not going to hold all three of you .
- Mike , climb off . - And go where ?
- Use that rack on your right . - Here , here .
JASON : Guys , just hang on , okay ?
Oh , shit , I can 't . I can 't .
Mike , look at me . Get off the goddamn shelf
before you get everybody killed .
Mike , man up .
Stop yelling at him , okay ? Stop .
Mike , I 'll move . I can move , okay ? Just stay there .
Just stay there . Don 't worry about it .
BEN : Just go , go .
Zoey . Hey , give me your hand .
Come on , give me your hand .
- Zoey , hey . Come on . - BEN : Careful .
Come on , give me your hand . Zoey . Zoey !
Zoey . Hey , Zoey .
[ SCREAMS ]
Oh , God !
- BEN : Goddamn it ! - JASON : Zoey !
You 've got to get up . Come on .
Zoey , wake up . Zoey , get off the floor .
Zoey , stay with me . Hey , you guys come on , I 'll go get her .
MAN [ ON RADIO ] : Come in , Vietnam Air 109 .
Come in , Vietnam Air 109 .
[ WHIMPERING ] Mom . Mom . Mom .
Mom . Mom . Mom .
[ CRYING ] Mama . Mom !
Zoey , come on , wake up .
Zoey , wake up . Zoey , come on .
We 've got to go . Zoey , come on !
We 're upside down .
Hey . Come on , come on .
[ GRUNTING ]
Hey , go , go .
The room is upside down , so the code might be , too .
Yeah , yeah , yeah .
ZOEY : Try zero-one-eight-six .
Zero-one-eight-six .
[ BEEPS ]
- I 've got it . - Okay , we 've got it . Come on .
- AMANDA : Zoey , you 're a genius . - JASON : Come on , hurry up .
Come on , Ben , hurry up . Hurry up .
- Come on . Hurry up . - Okay .
JASON : Come on , the floor 's going to drop .
[ DIAL-UP TONE SCREECHES ]
That is the second time this floor has tried to kill me .
Shit .
ZOEY : Come on , Jason .
I 've got it .
Okay .
- Okay . - ZOEY : Amanda , be careful .
[ ALL GASP ]
BEN : Hang on . Hang on .
ZOEY : All right , you 've got this .
Yes . Yes .
- All right . - MIKE : No , don 't look down .
AMANDA : Okay .
[ GRUNTS ]
[ DIAL-UP TONE SCREECHES ]
AMANDA : Okay .
- [ SONG RESUMES PLAYING ] - [ GRUNTING ]
You 've got it . You 've got it .
Okay .
Come on . Come on .
- Okay . - BEN : Shit . Oh , no .
Okay .
[ GROANS ]
- BEN : The ball ! - No !
BEN : Just let it go !
- ZOEY : Just leave it . - BEN : Hey , stop , stop !
[ GRUNTING ]
- Just leave it . - ZOEY : Amanda !
- [ ALL GASP ] - No !
- [ DIAL-UP TONE SCREECHES ] - JASON : Oh , shit !
Jason !
- I got it . The cord ! - ZOEY : Jump !
[ SCREAMS , GRUNTS ]
Hey , give me the pool cue .
MIKE : Yeah , good idea . Hang on .
Hang on , Amanda . Hang on . Come on , reach out there .
- Grab on to this , come on ! - MIKE : Grab it .
BEN : I can 't get it any farther .
ZOEY : Hey , you can do it .
You can do it . You can do it , Amanda .
You can do this . Just grab it , okay ?
MIKE : Grab on to it !
ZOEY : Come on , you got this . It 's just right there .
Amanda , listen to me . You can do it .
You can do this . We 're right here . Okay ? Stay . No .
It 's okay .
Amanda ! No , stay , okay ? Just hold on , just hold on . No !
No !
- No , no , no ! No , no ! - [ THUD ]
No , Amanda , no , no !
[ PANTING ]
[ GRUNTING ]
Zoey , come on . Hey , come on . Get out !
No .
[ DOOR SLAMS SHUT ]
[ ZOEY CRYING ]
[ ♪ ♪ ♪ ]
What in the hell is this supposed to be ?
- [ POWERING ON ] - [ GASPS ]
I don 't see a way out . Do you see anything ?
Hey , wunderkind , I need your brain . Get in here .
Zoey !
Will you give her a minute ? Amanda just died !
JASON : What don 't you people understand ?
We don 't have minutes to waste .
Amanda is dead . We aren 't .
Survival of the fittest .
Will you stop being a dick ?
What is your problem ?
Amanda wasn 't weak , okay ? She sacrificed herself for us !
Okay , well , then let 's not waste that sacrifice
by getting yourself killed .
[ LIGHTS CLICKING ON ]
This was my room .
Exactly the same .
This is my bed .
Me , too .
It 's Amanda 's .
IED blast .
She was the only survivor .
I was on a plane with my mom ...
backpacking across Vietnam .
The plane just crashed in the middle of the jungle .
It took them a week to find me .
I remember that .
You were on the news .
My college roommate and I took a boat out ...
and a wave came out of nowhere and just ...
flipped the boat over .
And I tried to grab a line and , uh ...
almost took my thumb off .
Wet ...
freezing , just holding on to the hull ...
with only one jacket between the two of us .
And Nathan , he started getting aggressive and confused .
It was signs of hypothermia ,
they told me later in the hospital .
Nathan , come back !
On the second day , he swam off .
I don 't know what he thought he saw out there ...
but there was nothing but ocean .
The next day , the Coast Guard found me alone .
What about you ?
I was the first of my friends to get a car .
It was winter break and we were having this ...
great night and ...
I wanted to take everybody out on a joy ride .
I was wasted .
[ MIKE CLEARS THROAT ]
Me and 11 others were working a mine in West Virginia ...
including my little brother , Cal .
There was a cave-in . Occupational hazard .
Me and Cal got pinned right next to each other .
I couldn 't see him , but I could , uh ...
I could hear him suffocating slowly .
I heard him take his last breath .
By the time the rescue crew got there ,
I was the only one alive .
They knew everything about us ...
every goddamn detail . I mean , they knew the jacket ...
that my roommate was wearing on that boat .
" Rudolph the Red-Nosed Reindeer , " that 's the ...
song that was playing when we crashed .
They made these rooms for us .
They addressed the boxes from people that we trust .
My nephew texted me , " Have a good time . "
- They hacked his goddamn phone . - It 's Danny 's .
Carbon monoxide poisoning .
Everyone in his family was killed but him .
None of us died , right ?
- We 're sole survivors . - JASON : So what ?
We 're a statistical improbability .
And now they want to see who will be
the luckiest among the lucky .
[ MUSIC PLAYS ON TV ]
MAN [ ON TV ] : Do you have the heart to let Dr. Wootan Yu ...
help you become a better you ?
Open new doors by testing your limits .
Don 't settle for a humdrum existence .
Live life to the extreme .
Place your order in the next five minutes
and receive a complimentary getaway .
MIKE : Okay , well , at least we know how much time we have .
Yeah , knowing exactly when I 'm going to die is a huge comfort .
Do you guys not understand ?
They chose us to die to see who 's the last person standing .
We need you on board right now , okay ? Stay with us .
We can 't just keep playing by their rules .
What else are we supposed to do ? They 're watching us .
They know every move that we 're making .
They 're watching us .
[ ♪ ♪ ♪ ]
I 've got something .
Come on , come on .
I got it . Here , here .
Uh . Okay . What do we have ?
A fist , one finger , and two fingers . It could be ...
It could be zero , one , two , right ? Right ? Like a code .
No , no , no . It spells ...
E-K-G .
Yeah , it 's sign language .
My cousin is deaf . They must have known about that , too .
Is there an EKG machine here somewhere ?
[ GLASS SHATTERS ]
[ GRUNTS ]
Hey , what are you doing ?
Quantum Zeno effect . Atoms won 't change
if you take continuous measurements ...
so as long as they 're watching us ,
we can 't change our state .
The game is designed so they always win .
[ GLASS SHATTERS ]
Okay , okay . We could really use your help right now .
No . We can find another way out .
JASON : We don 't even know the first way out .
Just stop smashing shit and take a deep breath .
MAN [ ON TV ] : Do you have the heart to let Dr. Wootan Yu
help you become a better you ?
BEN : Hey , Zoey , you need to calm down .
- [ ZOEY SCREAMS ] - [ GLASS SHATTERS ]
In three minutes , they 're going to poison us .
We are running out of time here . You 've got to calm down .
Stop telling me to calm down , okay ?
You 're not listening to me !
[ GLASS SHATTERS ]
You guys , it 's an EKG machine . Maybe this is our way out .
- Ben , take your shirt off . - What ? Why me ?
Because it 's the next clue , that 's why .
Come on , it 's just an EKG machine .
No , no . Nothing is just anything in this hellhole .
JASON : The right heart rate could open a door , Ben .
- We 're running out of time . - Hurry up .
Just do it . Come on .
Come on . Hold those , hold those . Take a breath , take a breath .
- [ BEEPING ] - [ GLASS SHATTERS ]
JASON : Your heart rate 's too low . Your heart rate 's too low .
It 's not working .
Somebody else has to do it .
Mike , we need a higher rate . You 've got to go .
What ? I 'm not your guinea pig , man . You do it . You try it .
Look . Ben is fine , man . Come on ,
I 'll go next . We need a higher rate . Come on .
All right . Okay . All right , let 's do it .
Zoey , please , just listen to me for two seconds .
[ GROANS ] Shit .
We 're in a metal box . Come on , that 's not going to help .
Just stop smashing shit and help me .
JASON : Higher , higher , higher . Come on !
- [ BEEPS ] - No .
MAN : Open new doors by testing your limits .
Testing your limits . Testing your limits .
- We need a higher rate . - You 're kidding me .
Man , I 'm already freaking out here .
My heart rate 's sky high .
Want me to do some burpees , jumping jacks ?
What do you want me to do ?
- We 've got these . - What are you , insane ?
When the Coast Guard found me dying from hypothermia ...
my heart was half dead , man .
These are what they used to bring me back .
Come on , this is what they used .
No , no . That is not an option .
Listen , it is a clue . They put it in my room
because they knew I would know , Mike .
Your heart 's already high . Man up , come on .
Are you kidding me ? Get these away from me .
Look at me , goddamn it ! Look at me !
In one minute , they 're about to poison us .
And we are going to suffocate , all right ?
We 're going to run out of breathable air ,
just like you did in that mine .
Shit .
You think about your brother , Cal .
Cal was his name , right ? This is your time .
Mike , you can save us .
This is it . You could save us , Mike .
- Now , save us . - Okay .
Do it . Do it , do it quick ! Come on , do it !
[ DEFIBRILLATOR POWERING UP ]
[ YELLS ]
[ SCREAMING ]
- BEN : Jason , what are you doing ? - That 's it .
BEN : No . No .
- Hey , don 't . Stop ! - Get off me !
[ DEFIBRILLATOR POWERING UP ]
You 're going to kill him !
- [ BEEPING ] - Come on !
Mike ? What did you do ?
He stopped breathing ! Mike !
Wake up ! Mike . Hey , stop ! Stop !
Come on !
Come on , Mike !
MAN : Open new doors by testing your limits .
Testing your limits .
[ WHIMPERING ]
High and low . High and low .
One , two . Goddamn it . Fuck !
[ ALARM WAILING ]
Oh , shit .
I don 't actually know how to do this .
What the hell are you doing ?
Extremes . Maybe they mean the low end .
[ GASPING ]
Hey , come on .
[ COUGHING ]
BEN : Come on , man .
Come on . Shit .
Mike .
[ COUGHING ]
[ BEEPING ]
The door . The door is opening . It opened .
[ COUGHING ]
BEN : Zoey . Hey !
Zoey !
Zoey ! Hey , come on . There 's a way out .
This is the way out .
You 'll suffocate , come on !
Just go !
- BEN : Please ! - Just go !
[ GASPING ]
Shit .
[ ♪ ♪ ♪ ]
[ WHEEZING ]
We should have made her come with us .
We just left her there to die .
She made her decision .
What the hell is wrong with you ?
What happened back there ?
I saved our asses . You 're welcome .
You killed Mike .
[ THUD ]
Sitting on his ass 12 hours a day killed him .
If it wasn 't that room , it would 've been the next .
So that 's just something you do , isn 't it ?
Your friend on the boat ?
What are you saying , Ben ? Huh ?
Use your words .
One jacket between the two of you .
Give me your jacket !
It 's pretty convenient that he just swam off and died .
You don 't want to do this , man .
You being the sole survivor had nothing to do with luck .
Admit it .
You killed him ! Admit that you killed your friend .
Surviving is a choice !
- Make yours . - [ WHIMPERING ]
[ COUGHING ]
Keep your eyes open and look for clues .
Hey , it 's a hatch .
I guess we just open it .
What are we letting in ?
Fine , I 'll do it .
- [ GRUNTS ] It 's heavy . - Come on , try harder .
Asshole , I don 't go to the gym every day .
Goddamn it .
[ BOTH GRUNTING ]
Come on , come on .
[ BOTH PANTING ]
What 's this shit on my hands ?
[ ♪ ♪ ♪ ]
I don 't feel so good .
[ DISTORTED ] Hey , hey .
They put something on the handle .
Hey , you 're melting . You 're melting .
- [ DISTORTED ] What ? - You 're melting .
What ? Wait . Look , look . It says something .
" Feel free to leave , but may we note ...
it 's best to find the antidote . "
How the hell are we supposed to do that ?
[ GROANS ]
[ SCREAMS ]
[ LAUGHING ]
Get up and look , goddamn it !
Who cares , man ? We 're going to die here anyway .
I 'm not going to die . I 'm not going to die .
[ LAUGHING ]
Okay .
[ GRUNTING ]
Where is it ? Come on . Come on . Where is it ?
- Where is this bastard ? - Where is it ?
JASON : Ben . Ben .
- I have the anti ... - Give me that !
[ BOTH GRUNTING ]
BEN : It 's mine !
- [ BONE CRUNCHES ] - [ BEN SCREAMS ]
[ BEN YELLS ]
[ GRUNTS ]
[ WHIMPERING ]
Shit .
[ PANTING ]
Oh , shit .
[ GRUNTS ]
[ PANTING ]
Oh , my God .
Okay , I 've got ten numbers , four spots .
I need a four-digit code .
[ RUMBLING ]
MAN : Entering room five . Stand by .
WOMAN [ OVER RADIO ] : Standing by .
MAN : We have two bodies . Over .
WOMAN : Copy .
20 minutes for disposal and cleanup . Over .
MAN : Copy . Out .
MAN : Look at that , the oxygen mask .
What the hell was she going to do with that ?
Breathe , bitch !
[ GRUNTING ]
[ SCREAMING ]
[ CRUNCHING ]
Shit .
[ GROANS ]
[ PANTING ]
[ GRUNTING AND GROANING ]
MAN [ OVER SPEAKERS ] : Now , you were a dark horse .
My money was on Jason .
But , see , that 's why these games are so fascinating .
Somehow , after being burnt ,
frozen , poisoned , and crippled ...
you still managed to escape the final room .
Did you ever think you had that in you ?
That adrenaline , that drive ?
Sit down . Celebrate .
You won something for once .
So , you 're the psycho that designed this murder maze , huh ?
No , I 'm the Games Master .
The Puzzle Maker designs the rooms .
But you kill people for fun . There 's nothing good left on TV ?
You killed all your friends ...
because you didn 't want to pay for a goddamn cab .
I wouldn 't get too comfortable on that high horse , Ben .
From the beginning of civilization ...
we 've known there was something captivating ...
about watching human beings fight for their lives .
That 's why we watch gladiator games , public executions ...
rubber-necking on the freeway .
But now the world 's gone soft .
Everything is safe . Everything is careful .
So , we created a sport for people
who still have a thirst for savagery ...
and we provided them with a box seat
for life 's ultimate drama .
Our customers are some of the most powerful
people in the world .
But every year , they demand more .
More complicated rooms .
More interesting subjects .
More ways to gamble on life and death .
Last year , they had college athletes ...
the year before , savants ...
and this year we had lone survivors .
They wanted to know if luck had anything to do with it .
Lucky people don 't get kidnapped and tortured by psychopaths .
You know , it 's kind of hurtful
when you call someone a psychopath , huh ?
I thought it was stupid , too .
But here you are ...
our lowest-odds ever to win ...
still alive .
I really didn 't think it was possible ...
but as I said ...
you were the long shot .
[ STAMMERING ] So I won .
That means I get to go home , right ?
Ben ...
at the end of the Kentucky Derby ...
do you think the horse gets a prize ?
[ GAGGING ]
Shh ...
Shh , shh ...
[ YELLS ]
[ BOARD CHIMES ]
Hey . Hey , Ben .
Come on . Hey , Ben , come on . Come on .
[ PANTING ]
Ben .
Ben , come on , get up . Ben , come on , get up .
[ ROARS ]
No !
[ SCREAMS ]
You can 't leave until we finish our game , Zoey .
[ BEN YELLS ]
Okay , we have to make sure that ...
He 's dead .
[ BOTH PANTING ]
[ ♪ ♪ ♪ ]
Okay . Come on . Come on .
Come on , there 's a service elevator .
You came back for me .
Yeah , well , I 'm tired of being the only survivor .
- BEN : Zoey , go , go . - ZOEY : Okay .
NURSE : It 's been 24 hours . He 's stable now .
You should get some rest .
WOMAN [ IN DISTANCE ] : He 's ready .
MAN [ ON PA ] : Dr. Bell , please come to the OR .
Dr. Bell , OR , please .
Miss Davis ?
Are you feeling well enough to come with me ?
[ SIRENS CHIRPING ]
Yeah , you 're right , we 'll have to check that for roof access .
[ ♪ ♪ ♪ ]
OFFICER : All right , everyone , 360 .
DETECTIVE : Miss Davis .
Wait , this was the waiting room . Okay ?
And then it turned into a giant oven , okay ?
And there was fire . The fire came down from the ceiling .
We haven 't found any evidence of the things you 've described .
That . Look . This was the duct .
There was a painting that came down .
Have you ever seen things that weren 't there before ?
I am not imagining this , okay ?
Look , Ben was there , too .
He 'll tell you all this when he wakes up .
DETECTIVE : Right . Your friend , Ben Miller ?
We got a report from the hospital .
They found traces of three different
illegal substances in his bloodstream .
" No way out . "
- DETECTIVE : Miss Davis . - It 's an anagram .
AMANDA : Dr. Wootan Yu .
MAN [ ON TV ] : Do you have the heart to let Dr. Wootan Yu help you ...
No way out . Wootan Yu .
- " Wootan Yu " is " No way out . " - DETECTIVE : Miss Davis .
No way out , Wootan Yu .
This . Look . That was a part of the game .
This is part of the game !
We 've got to vacate the premises .
[ ♪ ♪ ♪ ]
[ ZOEY PANTING ]
Wootan Yu . Wootan Yu .
[ SCREAMS ]
[ SHIP HORN HONKS ]
Thank you .
[ GRUNTS ]
So , are you going to tell me what 's going on ?
I am the new regional sales rep for all of Logan Square .
I 'm officially client facing . It 's for vegan dog food ...
but , you know , you 've got to start somewhere .
I 'm really proud of you .
Is that homework ?
What is this ?
Mike Nolan died of a heart attack
in a bathroom in Union Station .
Jason Walker was thrown from his bike on the I-64 ...
DMT found in his system .
Danny Khan drowns in Lake Michigan .
Amanda Harper , rock-climbing alone ,
because that makes sense ...
falls and dies .
There would have been articles for us , too .
You 've got to let this shit go .
I can 't just pretend that they never existed .
Everyone else who was sent those invitations died ...
and whoever sent them is still out there .
Don 't you want answers ? We can find them .
They rigged the game so that we would lose and we won .
We beat them at their own game .
I didn 't have a lot to go on , but ...
the logo ...
it 's an impossible object .
It 's an Escher staircase that turns in on itself .
It 's totally unique .
The numbers are in a pattern on the staircase .
23 , 22 in a repeated sequence of right angles .
They 're coordinates ...
for an unlisted industrial building
in the middle of Manhattan .
They 're hiding in plain sight .
What are we supposed to do with that ?
- I bought us plane tickets . - Plane tickets ?
Two weeks , I 'm going .
Zoey , it 's called " survivor 's guilt . "
My therapist says that in order to live , you need to move on .
Moving on doesn 't mean running .
And I 'm done running . Are you in ?
[ SIGHS ]
All right .
Yeah , I 'm in . Let 's do it .
You 're not Jason Bourne , though .
[ CHUCKLES SOFTLY ]
- Okay ? - Mm-hmm .
[ ♪ ♪ ♪ ]
Come on . It 's got to be in here .
[ PEOPLE CLAMORING ]
Found it ! X marks the spot .
Come on , come on , where is it ?
This has to be it , right ? I 've got the tool !
[ PEOPLE SCREAMING ]
Right here . It must connect to the bolt we found .
Okay .
Try it on the door . See if it 'll turn .
You can do it .
- Anything ? - It 's not going !
- See if you can turn it . - It 's not working !
- Try clockwise . - Clockwise ?
- Yeah , clockwise ! - Okay .
- Something happened here . - What ?
- COMPUTER : Terrain , terrain . - What 's this ?
No , it 's another riddle .
" I fly without wings , I cry without eyes . "
- What does that mean ? - I don 't know . Give me a second !
Heads down !
Brace for impact !
- Wait , " cloud " ! Try " cloud " ! - " Cloud " ?
- Yeah , " cloud . " - Okay .
Try the door ! Come on , let 's go !
COMPUTER : Pull up . Caution , terrain . Decision height .
Terrain , terrain . Pull up .
No , no ! Come on ! Come on !
COMPUTER : Caution , terrain . Terrain , terrain .
Do something !
COMPUTER : Pull up . Decision height . Pull up .
[ SCREAMS ]
Ending sim . Do you want to reset ?
PUZZLE MAKER [ DISTORTED VOICE ] : No . Good work . We 're ready for game time .
I hurt my goddamn hand on that bolt again , Larry .
WOMAN [ OVER SPEAKER ] : Deboard the simulator .
[ DISTORTED ] What 's the probability of survival ?
It 's approximately four percent .
PUZZLE MAKER : Well , it 's not a game if she doesn 't stand any chance .
We 've intercepted her flight information . It 's on .
I 'm so glad Zoey got over her fear of flying .
Let 's play again .
[ ♪ ♪ ♪ ]
Subtitles by explosiveskull